[ Screaming ] [ Helicopter Blades Whirring ]
- NOTHIN ' , NOTHIN ' AT ALL . - SEND IT AGAIN .
I 'VE BEEN SENDIN ' IT UP AND DOWN THE COAST FROM SARASOTA TO THE EVERGLADES .
IT 'S STILL GETTING BACK THE SAME DAY IT AIRED .
THERE 'S NOTHING . THERE 'S NOBODY , OR AT LEAST NOBODY WITH A RADIO .
ALL RIGHT THEN . LET 'S SET DOWN . WE 'LL USE THE BULLHORN .
[ Man ] SET DOWN ? WAIT A MINUTE . THAT 'S NOT IN OUR CONTRACT .
IT 'S THE BIGGEST CITY WITHIN 150 MILES . WE 'RE GONNA GIVE IT EVERY CHANCE .
JESUS , MARY AND JOSEPH . SET DOWN , JOHN .
I 'LL SET US DOWN , BUT I WON 'T LEAVE MY SEAT , AND I 'LL KEEP THE ENGINE RUNNING .
NOW , THE FIRST SIGN OF TROUBLE , I 'M GOING UP .
IF YOU AIN 'T ON BOARD WHEN THAT HAPPENS , YOU 'RE LIKELY TO HAVE A LOUSY AFTERNOON .
CALLING ANYBODY ON THIS FREQUENCY .
THIS IS HELICOPTER 4-0-ALPHA .
IF YOU CAN HEAR ME , PLEASE LISTEN CAREFULLY .
HELLO ?
HELLO ? IS ANYONE THERE ?
IS ANYONE THERE ?
[ Flies Buzzing ] IS ANYONE THERE ?
[ Wind Whistling ]
HELLO ?
IS THERE ANYONE THERE ?
[ Footsteps Approaching ]
[ Gasping ]
HELLO ?
[ Moaning ]
IS THERE ANYONE THERE ?
- [ Gasping ] - HELLO ?
[ Moaning ] HELLO ?
IS ANYONE THERE ?
HELLO ? [ Grunting ]
[ Low Moaning ]
[ Moaning Intensifies ]
WE CAN LIFT YOU OUT TO SAFETY . PLEASE ANSWER MY CALL IF YOU CAN HEAR ME .
FORGET IT , BILLY BOY . IT 'S A DEAD PLACE .
THEY GOT THE OTHERS , YOU KNOW .
LISTEN . [ Muffled Moaning ]
YOU CAN HEAR IT OVER THE ENGINE .
JESUS , MARY AND JOSEPH .
[ Moaning Nears ]
[ Helicopter Blades Whirring ]
[ Low Moaning ]
HEY , YOU FIND ANYTHING ?
YEAH . A BUNCH OF REAL ESTATE FOR SALE AT CLOSEOUT PRICES , MAN .
GAS UP THE MACHINE . SHE 'S DOWN TO FUMES .
NO . WAIT TILL IT 'S DARK . THERE ARE TOO MANY OF THEM OUT THERE .
YEAH-HEY , IT 'S NO GOOD TO LEAVE THE GAS TANK EMPTY .
- SUPPOSE WE NEED TO GET OUT OF HERE IN A HURRY . - THEN WE 'RE SHIT OUT OF LUCK .
THEY 'RE GETTING TOO RILED UP . DO IT TONIGHT WHEN THEY CAN 'T SEE YOU .
THEY KNOW WE 'RE IN HERE EVEN IF THEY CAN 'T SEE US . WHAT GOOD IS IT TO LEAVE THE GAS TANK EMP- -
THE ACTIVITY EXCITES THEM . THERE ARE TOO MANY OF THEM . AND MORE AND MORE EVERY DAY .
IF WE GET A LOT MORE , COME OUT AND SHOOT SOME . OTHERWISE , STAY INSIDE THE BUILDING .
STAY OUT OF SIGHT . BE THANKFUL YOU LIVE IN THE SUBURBS , JOHNSON .
YOU OUGHTA SEE HOW CONGESTED THE CITY 'S GETTIN ' TO BE .
MIGUEL , COME ON . LET 'S GET BELOW .
MIGUEL , WHAT CAN I DO ? YOU- - YOU- - WHAT ?
LET ME HELP . NO . I- - I DON 'T NEED HELP . I DON 'T NEED HELP .
COME ON . GIVE ME THIS . I 'M ALL RIGHT . I 'M JUST TIRED .
YOU 'RE NOT . YOU 'RE COLLAPSING FROM STRESS . NOW , LET ME HELP- - COLLAPSING FROM STRESS ?
WE 'RE ALL COLLAPSING . THIS WHOLE FUCKING UNIT IS COLLAPSING- -
EVERYBODY EXCEPT YOU .
I KNOW YOU 'RE STRONG , ALL RIGHT ? SO WHAT ?
STRONGER THAN ME . STRONGER THAN EVERYONE . SO WHAT ?
SO FUCKING WHAT ?
[ Moaning Continues ]
- THAT 'S A NEW GRAVE . - MAJOR COOPER . HE DIED THIS MORNING .
AND THEN THERE WERE 12 .
A BURIAL THIS MORNING . THAT 'S WHY THERE ARE SO MANY OF THEM .
WHAT 'S GONNA BRING THEM TOMORROW , SARAH ? AND THE NEXT DAY AND THE NEXT DAY AFTER ?
THERE ARE HUNDREDS OF ' EM OVER THERE , THOUSANDS . A MILLION OF THEM !
YOU STICK YOUR HEAD IN THE SUN , THEY 'RE GONNA COME UP BEHIND YOU AND BITE OFF YOUR ASS !
THIS IS BULLSHIT . CRAZY . IF YOU 'VE GOT AN ALTERNATIVE , WE 'D BE HAPPY TO LISTEN TO IT .
I GOT AN ALTERNATIVE . YEAH , YEAH . I GOT AN ALTERNATIVE .
LET 'S GET IN THAT WHIRLYBIRD , FIND US AN ISLAND SOMEPLACE , GET JUICED UP ...
AND SPEND WHAT TIME WE GOT LEFT SOAKIN ' UP SOME SUNSHINE .
HOW 'S THAT ? YOU COULD DO THAT , COULDN 'T YOU ?
WITH ALL THAT 'S GOING ON , YOU COULD DO THAT WITHOUT A SECOND THOUGHT ?
RIGHT . I COULD DO THAT EVEN IF ALL THIS WASN 'T GOIN ' ON .
[ Hydraulic Whirring ]
[ Electronic Beeping ]
ANOTHER WASTE OF TIME , RIGHT ? GOT THAT RIGHT , MAN .
[ Whirring ]
WHAT 'D YOU FIND ? NOTHIN ' .
NOTHIN ' ? HOW FAR UP THE COAST DID YOU GO ?
- A HUNDRED MILES EACH WAY . - [ Groans ]
JUMP IN HERE , SOLDIER . WE GOTTA BRING IN TWO MORE DUMB FUCKS . LET 'S GO .
- [ Sarah ] TWO MORE ? WHAT 'S LOGAN DOING TO THEM IN THERE ? - [ Man ] GET IN HERE .
HE 'S BEEN AWAKE FOR 24 HOURS . CAN 'T YOU GET ANYONE ELSE ?
WHAT " ANYONE ELSE " ? THERE ISN 'T ANYONE ELSE . WE 'RE IT .
THE TWO OF YOU CAN 'T GO IN THERE ALONE . IT 'S TOO DANGEROUS .
CHRIST . I 'LL GO !
- WHAT 'S THE MATTER WITH YOUR FRIEND THERE ? - THERE 'S NOTHING THE MATTER .
ALL RIGHT . LET 'S GO .
[ Man Talking , Indistinct ]
[ Man # 2 ] YOU GOT IT , STEEL .
[ Men Continue Chattering , Indistinct ]
[ Man Laughing Maniacally ]
[ Screeching ]
[ Maniacal Laughter Continues ]
LET 'S KICK IT OUT . COME ON . STEP FORWARD .
[ Mechanical Whirring ]
[ Spitting ]
[ Wind Whistling ]
THIS SHOWS THE 15th AS THE LAST TIME YOU TOOK ANY OUT .
THAT CAN 'T BE RIGHT . OH , YEAH . WE FORGET TO WRITE ' EM UP SOMETIMES .
YOU 'VE GOT TO WRITE THEM UP . IT 'S ESSENTIAL .
CAN 'T YOU GET THAT THROUGH YOUR THICK SKULL ?
HOW THE HELL ARE WE SUPPOSED TO KEEP TRACK OF HOW MANY WE GOT LEFT ?
[ Screaming ]
[ Whistling ]
LET 'S GO , YOU DUMB FUCKS ! GET OVER HERE !
HEY ! HERE WE ARE !
[ Low Moaning ] COME ON !
[ Steel ] COME ON , YOU DUMB FUCKS . COME ON . COME ON .
- [ Steel Knocking ] - COME ON , YOU FISH BRAINS . WHAT THE HELL 'S THE MATTER WITH YA ?
THEY 'RE SCARED . HUH ?
THEY KNOW WHAT 'LL HAPPEN WHEN FRANKENSTEIN GETS ' EM .
[ Sarah ] IF YOU 'RE RIGHT , RICKLES , THEN THEY 'RE LEARNING .
THEY 'RE ACTUALLY LEARNING . [ Steel ] COME ON !
COME AND SEE WHAT I GOT FOR YOU ! COME ON , YOU DICK FACES !
HERE 'S A NICE ONE HANGIN ' . COME ON . COME AND GET IT .
- COME AND TRY TO BITE IT OFF ! - THAT 'S IT . WHIP IT OUT . THAT 'LL BRING ' EM ON .
FUCKIN ' " A. " BIGGEST PIECE OF MEAT IN THE CAVE .
I DON 'T WANNA EXCITE THE LADY THOUGH . NOT WITH HER BOYFRIEND AROUND .
YOU 'RE INCAPABLE OF EXCITING ME , STEEL , EXCEPT AS AN ANTHROPOLOGICAL CURIOSITY .
- WHAT THE HELL 'S THAT MEAN , RICKLES ? - IT MEANS YOU 'RE A CAVEMAN .
YOU 'RE A FUCKIN ' THROWBACK . YOU 'VE BEEN SPENDIN' TOO MUCH TIME UNDERGROUND , HUH ?
IT 'S OKAY , STEEL . THROWBACKS ALL GOT BIG DICKS .
OH ! [ Laughs Hysterically ]
ALL RIGHT , YOU DUMB FUCKS ! GET OVER HERE , YOU SCUMBAGS !
YOUR OLD PAL STEEL WANTS TO SEE YA . [ Growls ]
- SHIT . - I 'M COMING UP .
YOU 'RE NOT STRONG ENOUGH FOR UP HERE . SEND UP THE POLE . I 'LL WATCH OUT FOR LOVER BOY .
DON 'T WORRY . I 'M NOT STRONG ENOUGH ? I 'VE DONE IT DOZENS OF TIMES .
I DON 'T WANT YOU UP HERE , LADY . SEND UP THE POLE . THEY 'RE GETTIN ' CLOSER .
HE 'S CLAMPING . LOOK AT ' IM . LET GO OF THE POLE .
LISTEN TO ME . LET GO OF THE GODDAMN POLE .
- HERE THEY COME ! LET 'S GO ! - [ Moaning Continues ]
DUMB FUCKS . PUS-BREEDING BAGS OF SHIT .
YOU DUMB-FUCKING BAGS OF SHIT , I 'LL KICK YOUR FUCKIN ' ASSES . COME ON !
- [ All Growling , Moaning ] - [ Laughing Mockingly ]
COME HERE , SCUMBAG . [ Continues Laughing ]
[ Growling ]
[ Steel ] HOOK HER UP , WILL YA ? HOOK HER . [ Growling ]
HEY , NICE HAT , ASSHOLE .
[ Screeching ]
COME ON ! GET THE OTHER ONE OUT OF THERE !
[ Zombie Grunting , Screeching ]
[ Continues Grunting ]
- [ Steel Shouting , Indistinct ] - [ Screaming ]
STEEL , STEEL , STEEL , COVER ! COVER !
- [ Steel ] I GOT IT . - GEEZ .
THAT 'S IT . THAT 'S IT . THAT 'S IT . I GOT IT . I GOT IT . COME ON .
COME ON . COME HERE . COME HERE . [ Zombie Continues Growling ]
YOU ALMOST KILLED RICKLES . YEAH . YOU ALMOST KILLED RICKLES .
- [ Screaming ] - LET ' IM GO , STEEL .
- HE SHOULDN 'T HAVE BEEN UP THERE IN THE FIRST PLACE . - [ Yelling , Indistinct ]
STEEL , STOP IT ! [ Continues Roaring ]
YOU DIRTY SON OF A BITCH ! LET HIM GO ! LET HIM GO ,
GODDAMN IT , OR I 'LL CUT YOU IN HALF .
[ Growling ]
[ Growling ] [ All Yelling , Indistinct ]
SHUT UP , YOU DUMB FUCKS . I HOPE THEY CHOP YOU UP FOR DOG MEAT .
COME ON , RICKLES . LET 'S GET OUT OF HERE .
I HOPE YOU FUCKIN ' ROT ! FUCK YOU !
[ Groaning , Whimpering ]
I AM NOT GONNA LET YOU DOPE ME UP .
YOU NEED A SEDATIVE . YOU 'RE BEHAVING DANGEROUSLY .
- I 'M JUST TRYING TO HELP YOU , MIGUEL . - WELL , I DON 'T NEED YOUR HELP .
YOU MADE ME LOOK LIKE AN ASSHOLE OUT THERE .
YOU MADE ME FEEL LIKE A PIECE OF SHIT .
YOU STAY AWAY FROM ME WITH THAT , SARAH .
- YOU STAY AWAY FROM ME . - [ Gasping ]
OHH . [ Crying ]
[ Shrieks ]
[ Gasping ]
YOU BITCH .
[ Groans , Sobs ]
WE 'VE GOT TO HAVE STERILE CONDITIONS . HALF THE WORK WE DO ...
GOES DOWN THE TOILET DUE TO CONTAMINATION .
YOU 'LL WORK WITH WHAT YOU GOT , FISHER . BUT IT 'S MADNESS !
- CAN 'T YOU UNDERSTAND- - - I UNDERSTAND THIS : YOU AND YOUR PLAYMATES ,
YOU 'RE RUNNING OUT OF FRIENDS FAST AROUND HERE .
[ Sighs ] LOOK , MAJOR COOPER PROMISED THAT- -
MAJOR COOPER IS DEAD .
I 'M IN COMMAND NOW , AND I 'M TELLING YOU ...
THAT YOU WORK WITH WHAT YOU GOT .
AND YOU 'D BETTER START SHOWING ME SOME RESULTS ...
OR YOU WON 'T HAVE THAT VERY MUCH LONGER .
HOW CAN WE SHOW YOU RESULTS WHEN WE DON 'T HAVE THE PROPER WORKING CONDITIONS ?
WE 'RE IN A DESPERATE SITUATION HERE . WE NEED EACH OTHER .
CAN 'T WE JUST GET ALONG ? [ Man ] YOU NEED US , THE WAY I SEE IT , LADY .
I 'M NOT SURE WE NEED YOU AT ALL . [ Steel ] FUCKIN ' " A. "
I 'M NOT EVEN SURE WHAT THE HELL IT IS YOU 'RE DOIN ' IN THERE ,
JUST WHAT THE HELL MY MEN ARE RISKIN ' THEIR ASSES FOR .
IF THERE WAS MORE COOPERATION , YOUR MEN WOULDN 'T HAVE TO RISK THEIR ASSES AS OFTEN .
[ Rifle Cocks ]
- MIGUEL SALAZAR 'S IN BAD SHAPE . - [ Chuckles ] NO SHIT .
I WANT HIM PULLED OFF ACTIVE DUTY FOR A WHILE UNTIL WE CAN EVALUATE HIS CONDITION .
- CAN 'T SPARE ' IM . - HE 'S OVER THE EDGE . HE 'S TURNING INTO JELL-O .
- JELL-O ? - THAT 'S THE WAY THE SPICKS SAY " YELLOW " : JELL-O !
MIGUEL IS SERIOUSLY DISTURBED . HE 'S CLOSE TO THE BREAKING POINT ,
AND THAT 'S DANGEROUS FOR ALL OF US .
HE CAN 'T HANDLE ANY MORE STRESS RIGHT NOW .
WELL , MAYBE I SHOULD CUT OFF HIS EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES .
MAYBE YOU 'RE KEEPIN ' HIM TOO BUSY AT NIGHT .
WE 'RE TALKING ABOUT A MAN 'S LIFE HERE , YOU SON OF A BITCH ,
AND THE LIVES OF OTHERS HE MIGHT PUT IN JEOPARDY .
MAYBE I SHOULD PUT HIM IN QUARANTINE . HOW ' BOUT IT , STEEL ?
YOU CALL IT , CAPTAIN . I 'LL BUILD HIM A CAGE .
[ Captain ] YEAH . MIGHT NOT BE A BAD IDEA- -
GIVE SOME OF THE REST OF US A SHOT AT SOME LOVIN ' .
[ Steel ] HEY , IT 'S GONNA BE A LONG WINTER .
COME ON , TED . LET 'S GET OUT OF HERE .
[ Captain ] I 'M CALLIN ' A MEETING FOR 7 : 00 TONIGHT .
I WANT EVERYBODY PRESENT . EVERYBODY , LADY ,
INCLUDING DR. FRANKENSTEIN AND INCLUDING YOUR BOYFRIEND .
- I GAVE HIM A SEDATIVE . HE WON 'T BE AWAKE . - LOOK HERE , WOMAN .
I 'M SHORT ON MAN POWER . I WON 'T HAVE YOU GOIN ' AROUND ...
DOPIN ' UP ANY OF MY MEN WITHOUT ORDERS FROM ME .
- IS THAT CLEAR ? - YES , SIR !
FUCK YOU , SIR !
[ Door Slams ]
OUT OF THE FRYING PAN , INTO THE FIRE .
I THOUGHT COOPER WAS AN ASSHOLE , BUT HE WAS A SWEETHEART NEXT TO RHODES .
WE COULD BE IN REAL TROUBLE . YOU 'D BETTER WATCH YOURSELF- - I MEAN , PHYSICALLY WATCH YOURSELF .
I CAN HANDLE IT . DON 'T WORRY . IT 'S NOT GOING TO COME TO THAT .
WE 'VE JUST GOTTA POUND SOME LOGIC INTO THEIR HEADS . IMPOSSIBLE .
[ Sighs ] WHERE 'S DR. LOGAN ?
FRANKENSTEIN ? HE 'S IN HIS LABORATORY . WHERE ELSE ?
[ Man ] THERE 'S A LOSS OF INITIATIVE , CAUTION , MANY OF THE HUMAN COGNITIVE FUNCTIONS .
APPARENTLY THE RESULT OF DECAY IN THE FRONTAL , PARIETAL ,
TEMPORAL AND OCCIPITAL LOBES .
ON REVIVAL , THE RATE OF DECOMPOSITION SLOWS SUBSTANTIALLY .
[ Switch Clicks ] INDICATIONS ARE THAT THESE BEINGS ...
COULD FUNCTION OVER A PERIOD OF YEARS- -
IN CASES OF EARLY REVIVAL , 10 TO 12 YEARS BEFORE DECAY WOULD THREATEN MOBILITY .
- [ Screams ] - [ Growls ]
[ Moaning ]
THE BRAIN IS THE ENGINE , SARAH , THE MOTOR THAT DRIVES THEM .
THEY DON 'T NEED ANY BLOOD FLOW , DON 'T NEED ANY OF THEIR INTERNAL ORGANS .
NOW , I 'VE SEVERED ALL THE VITAL ORGANS IN THIS ONE .
THERE 'S NOTHING LEFT OF THE CORPSE BUT BRAIN AND LIMBS , AND STILL IT FUNCTIONS .
OH , LOOK , SARAH . LOOK . [ Grunting ]
SEE , IT WANTS ME . IT WANTS FOOD , BUT IT HAS NO STOMACH .
IT CAN TAKE NO NOURISHMENT FROM WHAT IT INGESTS .
IT 'S WORKING ON INSTINCT , A DEEP , DARK , PRIMORDIAL INSTINCT .
DECOMPOSITION OCCURS FIRST IN THE FRONTAL LOBES , THE NEOCORTEX ,
AND NEXT IN THE LIMBIC SYSTEM , THE MIDDLE BRAIN .
BUT THE CORE- - THE CORE IS THE LAST THING TO BE ATTACKED BY THE DECAY .
IT 'S THE " R " COMPLEX , SARAH- - THAT CENTRAL BIT OF PREHISTORIC JELLY ...
THAT WE INHERITED FROM THE REPTILES .
HERE . I 'VE GONE INTO THE CENTER HERE AND ATTACKED THE " R " COMPLEX DISCRETELY .
I 'VE REMOVED IT FROM THE EQUATION- - THIS CORPSE .
I BELIEVE THIS CREATURE WOULD BE BENIGN EVEN IF IT HAD ITS EYESIGHT AND ITS OTHER SENSES .
ITS PRIMITIVE INSTINCTS HAVE BEEN ERASED .
[ Machine Whirring ]
IT STILL HAS MOTOR FUNCTION , PROBABLY STILL HAS POWERS OF DELIBERATION .
IT CAN BE DOMESTICATED , SARAH , DON 'T YOU SEE ?
IT CAN BE CONDITIONED TO BEHAVE THE WAY WE WANT IT TO BEHAVE .
AND ALL THAT 'S REQUIRED IS 15 HOURS OF FANCY SURGERY ...
THAT ONLY A HANDFUL OF PEOPLE ARE TRAINED TO DO .
WE WERE GOING TO STOP WORK ON THE NEUROPHYSICAL , CONCENTRATE ON SOMETHING MORE PRACTICAL .
THESE FINDS ARE CENTRAL TO THE CONDITION . I WILL NOT STOP WORK ...
THAT MIGHT LEAD TO AN ANSWER , LET ALONE IN AN AREA THAT IS CENTRAL TO THE CONDITION .
[ Exhales Forcefully ] BUT YOU 'RE JUST PROVING THEORIES THAT WERE ADVANCED MONTHS AGO .
AND YOU 'RE NOT EVEN PROVING THEM CORRECTLY . YOU 'RE MAKING A LOT OF ASSUMPTIONS .
YOU 'RE WASTING TIME TRYING TO DEFINE WHAT 'S HAPPENING ...
INSTEAD OF LOOKING FOR WHAT 'S MAKING IT HAPPEN .
AND JUST SLICING UP TOO MANY SPECIMENS . IT 'S EXTREMELY DANGEROUS ...
TO GO UP ON TOP AND ROUND THEM UP IN THE WILD .
WELL , WE CAN 'T CONTROL THEM . WHAT HAPPENED TO THIS ONE ?
[ Doctor ] IT WAS TOO UNRULY . I COULDN 'T HANDLE IT . I HAD TO DESTROY IT .
- WE CAN STILL GET INFORMATION FROM IT . - DR. LOGAN ,
WE ARE LOSING THE COOPERATION OF THE MEN .
I 'M NOT EVEN SURE THEY 'LL GO UP TOP WHEN WE RUN OUT OF THE SPECIMENS WE HAVE .
I 'M NOT SURE THEY WON 'T JUST TRY TO SHUT US DOWN COMPLETELY .
WELL , I 'LL SHOW THEM RESULTS . I 'LL SHOW THEM RESULTS .
I 'LL SHOW THEM THAT THESE CREATURES CAN BE DOMESTICATED EVEN WITHOUT THE SURGERY .
KNOWING WHAT THEY ARE , WE CAN BEGIN TO APPROACH THEM PROPERLY ,
CONDITION THEM , CONTROL THEM .
WE 'VE GOT TO DO THIS , SARAH . IT 'S OUR ONLY HOPE .
YES , THIS IS MAJOR COOPER .
I NEEDED HIM , SARAH . HE 'S HELPING US MORE NOW THAN HE EVER DID WHEN HE WAS ALIVE .
- BUT I SAW THE GRAVE . - THEY BURIED ONE OF THE SPECIMENS .
JESUS . GOD , LOGAN .
DO YOU KNOW WHAT THEY 'LL DO TO YOU IF THEY FIND OUT ABOUT THIS ?
- DO YOU KNOW WHAT THEY 'LL DO TO ALL OF US ? - THEY 'LL NEVER FIND OUT .
HE CAN 'T BE RECOGNIZED .
[ Moaning ]
[ Gasping ]
NOT A PEEP . LONG-RANGE OR SHORT , HIGH-BAND OR LOW , I CAN 'T RAISE ANYBODY .
[ Man ] HOW CAN THAT BE , McDERMOTT ? THERE MUST BE OTHER GROUPS LIKE US .
SOMEBODY ELSE MUST BE TRYIN' TO RADIO . YEAH . WHAT THE HELL IS THIS ?
MAYBE WE ARE THE ONLY ONES LEFT . I 'M SURE THERE 'S OTHERS .
THIS IS NOT THE BEST PLACE TO BE SENDING FROM , AND A LOT OF THE EQUIPMENT I 'M USING ...
HAS BEEN ROTTING DOWN HERE SINCE THE SECOND WORLD WAR .
WELL , IT 'S UP TO YOU TO GET IT WORKIN ' RIGHT .
LAY OFF THE FUCKIN ' BOOZE FOR A WHILE , WHY DON 'T YA ?
AND GET SOMEBODY ON THAT FUCKIN ' HORN , PRONTO .
WELL , IF WE STAY DOWN HERE LONG ENOUGH , I 'LL HAVE TO LAY OFF THE FUCKIN ' BOOZE , STEEL ,
'CAUSE THERE WON 'T FUCKIN' BE ANY OF IT FUCKIN ' LEFT .
IN THE MEANWHILE , I WILL CONTINUE TO INDULGE MYSELF , AND I WILL CONTINUE DOING MY BEST ...
IN THE GOOD FIGHT AGAINST DRY ROT AND RUST .
YEAH ? WELL , YOUR BEST AIN 'T GOOD ENOUGH , ASSHOLE .
YOU THINK I 'M NOT AWARE OF OUR SITUATION ? YOU THINK I WANT TO STAY ISOLATED DOWN HERE ?
YOU KNOW , I 'D MAKE A DESPERATE EFFORT TO RAISE SOMEBODY ...
JUST IN THE HOPE OF GETTIN ' AWAY FROM YOUR NASTY MOUTH , STEEL .
THE FACT IS- -
THE FACT IS ...
EITHER WE ARE THE ONLY ONES LEFT ...
OR THERE 'S NOBODY WITHIN RANGE OF MY PUNY LITTLE SECOND WORLD WAR SIGNALS .
WE USED TO TALK TO WASHINGTON ALL THE TIME . THEY COULD HEAR US THEN .
WE WERE ON RELAYS THEN . WE WEREN 'T OVER THE AIR .
YOU KNOW , THE POWER 'S OFF ON THE MAINLAND NOW , IN CASE YOU HAVEN 'T HEARD .
ALL THE SHOPPING MALLS ARE CLOSED . WE DON 'T APPRECIATE YOUR JOKES .
KEEP IT UP , AND I 'LL SHOVE THAT BOTTLE OF YOURS RIGHT UP YOUR WISE ASS .
I 'VE GOT BETTER THINGS TO DO THAN LISTEN TO THIS KINDERGARTEN . ARE WE FINISHED ?
NO , WE AIN 'T FINISHED HERE , LADY . SIT DOWN .
WHAT ELSE DO YOU WANT ? WE 'VE GIVEN YOU THE REPORTS FOR THIS WEEK .
WE 'VE GIVEN YOU EVERYTHING YOU 'VE ASKED FOR . YOU 'VE GIVEN US GREEK SALAD .
FORMULAS , EQUATIONS , A LOT OF FANCY TERMS THAT DON 'T MEAN A THING .
I WANNA KNOW IF YOU 'RE DOIN' SOMETHING THAT 'S GONNA HELP US OUT OF THIS DEEP SHIT WE 'RE IN ,
OR IF YOU 'RE ALL IN THERE JUST JERKIN ' EACH OTHER OFF .
SHE DOESN 'T HAVE TO JERK OFF LIKE THE REST OF US , CAPTAIN . SHE GOT AN HONEST-TO-GOD DICK ...
TO GET OFF ON , HUH ? [ Laughs Mockingly ]
IT MAY BE YELLOW , BUT IT 'S STILL A DICK !
[ Yells , Laughs ] [ Others Laugh ]
I SAID WE AIN 'T FINISHED HERE , LADY .
SIT DOWN .
SIT DOWN , OR SO HELP ME , GOD , I 'LL HAVE YOU SHOT .
- YOU 'LL WHAT ? - I SAID ,
" I 'LL HAVE YOU SHOT . "
HAVE YOU LOST YOUR MIND ? NO , MA 'AM .
HAVE YOU ? I JUST TOLD YOU I WAS WILLING TO KILL YOU IF YOU DIDN 'T GET BACK IN YOUR CHAIR .
YOU DIDN 'T GET BACK IN YOUR CHAIR .
GODDAMN IT ! YOU CAN 'T SHOVE US AROUND LIKE THIS .
SINCE WHEN DID THIS BECOME A MILITARY OPERATION ?
SINCE I TOOK OVER . STEEL , SHOOT THAT WOMAN .
BANG ! YOU 'RE DEAD .
SHOOT THAT WOMAN OR YOU 'RE DEAD .
YOU THINK I 'M FUCKIN ' AROUND , STEEL ?
YOU 'RE WRONG .
NOW , YOU GOT TILL A COUNT OF FIVE , AND THAT 'S TWO YOU WASTED .
- [ Spits ] - THAT 'S THREE .
- FOUR . - SIT DOWN , SARAH .
WHAT IS THIS ? SHUT UP AND SIT DOWN .
THAT 'S FIVE , STEEL . [ Gun Cocks ] ALL RIGHT .
ALL RIGHT .
- [ Gun Cocks ] - NO !
ANYBODY ELSE HAVE ANY QUESTIONS ABOUT THE WAY THINGS ARE GONNA RUN AROUND HERE FROM NOW ON ?
THIS AIN 'T A GODDAMN FIELD TRIP , PEOPLE .
THIS IS A FUCKIN ' WAR !
I 'M NOT DOWN IN THIS CAVE FOR MY HEALTH . I 'M DOWN HERE ON ORDERS .
YOUR ORDERS ARE TO FACILITATE THE JOB OF THIS SCIENTIFIC TEAM .
THIS IS A CIVILIAN TEAM , AND WE DON 'T HAVE TO BE SUBJECTED TO YOUR TYRANNY .
WHO 'S BEING SUBJECTED TO WHAT , FISHER ?
YOU 'VE LOST ONE MAN . [ Men ] YEAH . RIGHT .
WE 'VE LOST FIVE . [ Men Murmuring Agreement ]
WHERE DOES IT SAY WE GOTTA KEEP THOSE DUMB FUCKS NEXT DOOR TO WHERE WE SLEEP ?
WHERE DOES IT SAY WE SHOULD DO ANY ONE THING BUT SHOOT THE MOTHERS IN THE HEAD ?
[ Logan ] WE DON 'T HAVE ENOUGH AMMUNITION TO SHOOT THEM ALL IN THE HEAD .
THE TIME TO HAVE DONE THAT WOULD 'VE BEEN AT THE BEGINNING .
NO . WE LET THEM OVERRUN US . THEY HAVE OVERRUN US , YOU KNOW .
WE 'RE IN THE MINORITY NOW .
SOMETHING LIKE 400,000 TO ONE , BY MY CALCULATIONS .
I HAVEN 'T EATEN . IS THERE FOOD ?
YOU WERE SUPPOSED TO BE HERE AT 7 : 00 SHARP , MISTER .
I KNOW . SARAH TOLD ME . I 'M SORRY . I COULDN 'T BREAK AWAY . IS THERE FOOD ?
LISTEN , EGGHEAD , LET ME BRING YOU UP TO DATE ON WHAT 'S- - EXCUSE ME .
LET ME- - EXCUSE ME !
- IS THERE FOOD ? - I 'M RUNNIN ' THIS MONKEY FARM NOW , FRANKENSTEIN ,
AND I WANNA KNOW WHAT THE FUCK YOU 'RE DOIN ' WITH MY TIME !
'CAUSE IF WE 'RE JUST JERKIN ' OFF HERE ,
I 'M GONNA HAVE MY MEN BLOW THE PISS ...
OUT OF THOSE PRECIOUS SPECIMENS OF YOURS , [ Men Murmuring Agreement ]
AND WE 'RE GONNA GET THE HELL OUT OF HERE AND LEAVE YOU AND YOUR HIGHFALUTIN ASSHOLE FRIENDS ...
TO ROT IN THIS STINKIN ' SEWER !
IS THAT FOOD ENOUGH FOR YA ?
WHERE WILL YOU GO , CAPTAIN ? YOU CAN DESTROY MY SPECIMENS ,
BUT WHAT ABOUT THE MILLIONS MORE THAT ARE WAITING TO GREET YOU OUTSIDE ?
DO YOU REALLY THINK YOU CAN " BLOW THE PISS " OUT OF THEM ?
ALL OF THEM ? THEY HAVE YOU IN A HOPELESS SITUATION , STRATEGICALLY .
YOU 'RE LOST . WELL , YOU 'RE LOST UNLESS- -
UNLESS WHAT ? UNLESS WHAT , FRANKENSTEIN ?
- UNLESS YOU CAN MAKE THEM BEHAVE . - [ Men Scoffing ]
THIS IS A FUCKIN ' LOONY BIN ! I AIN 'T BEIN ' PAID ENOUGH TO WORK IN A FUCKIN ' LOONY BIN !
- I AIN 'T BEIN ' PAID AT ALL ! - PAID ? WHAT THE HELL ARE THEY PAYIN ' HIM FOR ?
[ Captain ] ALL RIGHT . SHUT UP ! JUST SHUT UP !
WHAT THE HELL ARE YOU TALKIN ' ABOUT , FRANKENSTEIN ?
I 'LL BE ABLE TO SHOW YOU SOON ENOUGH . SARAH KNOWS .
SHE 'S SEEN THE PROGRESS I 'VE BEEN MAKING . ISN 'T THAT RIGHT , SARAH ?
YES . THERE 'S BEEN SOME PROGRESS .
WHAT KIND OF PROGRESS ?
WHAT ARE YOU TALKIN ' ABOUT , " MAKE THEM BEHAVE " ? WHAT DOES THAT MEAN ?
IT MEANS KEEPING THEM FROM WANTING TO EAT US , FOR ONE THING .
IT MEANS KEEPING THEM IN CHECK , CONTROLLING THEM .
- CONTROLLING THEM . - WHEN ARE YOU GONNA SHOW US SOMETHING WE CAN UNDERSTAND ?
VERY CLOSE . VERY CLOSE . I THINK IN A MATTER OF WEEKS- -
I DON 'T THINK THERE 'S ANY WAY YOU CAN TELL HOW LONG ANYTHING IS GOING TO TAKE .
IT COULD BE MONTHS ; IT COULD BE YEARS BEFORE WE KNOW EXACTLY WHAT WE 'RE DEALING WITH .
[ Men Murmuring ] SARAH 'S RESEARCH- -
[ Louder ] SARAH 'S RESEARCH IS MORE ESOTERIC THAN MINE . [ Murmuring Stops ]
SHE 'S LOOKING FOR A WAY TO REVERSE THE PROCESS , A WAY TO ERADICATE THE PROBLEM .
THAT COULD TAKE A LONG TIME , A VERY LONG TIME .
SHE MAY NEVER FIND WHAT SHE 'S LOOKING FOR .
WE HAVE A LIMITED SUPPLY OF CHEMICAL AGENTS .
OUR EQUIPMENT IS HOPELESSLY INADEQUATE .
McDERMOTT DOESN 'T HAVE DECENT RADIO GEAR .
NOW YOU 'RE TELLIN ' ME THAT YOU DON 'T HAVE THE SHIT YOU NEED ?
WE 'RE RUNNIN ' LOW ON AMMUNITION . WE 'RE RUNNIN ' LOW ON MEN , FOR CHRISSAKES !
IT WAS VERY RUSHED . THIS OPERATION WAS PUT TOGETHER IN A MATTER OF DAYS .
YEAH , WELL , IT CAN ALL BE TAKEN APART IN A MATTER OF MINUTES , LADY ,
AND I 'M HERE TO TELL YOU THAT I 'M READY TO DO THAT LITTLE THING .
I 'M READY TO TAKE THE NEXT TRAIN OUTTA HERE !
[ Logan ] I ASK YOU AGAIN , CAPTAIN : WHERE WILL YOU GO ?
YOU HAVE NO CHOICES . YOU 'LL HAVE TO GIVE US THE WEEKS THAT WE 'VE ASKED FOR .
YOU HAVE TO GIVE US HOWEVER LONG IT TAKES . LOOK .
THERE HAVE TO BE SURVIVORS IN WASHINGTON . [ Man ] MY ASS .
THEY HAVE MORE SOPHISTICATED SHELTERS THAN THIS ONE . [ Man ] BULLSHIT .
THERE HAVE TO BE PEOPLE IN THOSE SHELTERS WHO KNOW ABOUT US , WHO KNOW WHERE WE ARE .
WITH NO RADIO CONTACT , THEY 'LL COME LOOKING FOR US .
- [ Men Murmuring ] - I SAID SHUT UP !
YOU GOT A LITTLE MORE TIME .
A LITTLE MORE . I AIN 'T SAYIN ' HOW MUCH .
BUT YOU 'D BETTER START SHOWIN ' ME SOME RESULTS , AND YOU 'D BETTER NOT PISS ME OFF .
YOU UNDERSTAND ? NOTHIN ' HAPPENS AROUND HERE WITHOUT MY KNOWIN ' ABOUT IT !
AND ANYBODY FUCKS WITH MY COMMAND ,
THEY GET COURT-MARTIALED , THEY GET EXECUTED .
YOU 'D BETTER KNOW I MEAN IT , TOO , PEOPLE .
[ Men Murmuring ] HE WOULDN 'T HAVE DONE IT . I CAN 'T BELIEVE HE WOULD 'VE .
NO , HE WOULDN 'T HAVE DONE IT .
- HE WOULD 'VE HAD STEEL DO IT . - HE CAN 'T BE THAT INHUMAN .
NO . HE 'S HUMAN . THAT 'S WHAT SCARES ME , YOU KNOW .
HE WON 'T SHOOT BILLY ' CAUSE HE DOESN 'T HAVE ANYBODY ELSE WHO KNOWS ELECTRONICS .
HE WON 'T SHOOT ME , 'CAUSE I 'M HIS RIDE .
HE PROBABLY WON 'T SHOOT OLD FRANKENSTEIN , ' CAUSE THE OLD DOC CAN TALK HIM SILLY .
BUT THE REST OF YOU ...
BETTER START WORRYING , YOU KNOW .
MAYBE IF WE TRIED WORKING TOGETHER , WE COULD EASE SOME OF THE TENSIONS .
- WE 'RE ALL PULLING IN DIFFERENT DIRECTIONS . - THAT 'S THE TROUBLE , SARAH .
PEOPLE GOT DIFFERENT IDEAS CONCERNING WHAT THEY WANT OUT OF LIFE .
[ Gasps ]
YOU ARE AFRAID , AREN 'T YOU ?
JUST AS AFRAID AS I AM .
WHY DON 'T YOU TAKE A SEDATIVE , SARAH , SO YOU CAN SLEEP ?
YOU 'RE FULL OF SHIT , SARAH , YOU KNOW THAT ? YOU 'RE REALLY FULL OF SHIT .
I 'M THROUGH WITH YOU .
FINE THEN . GET OUT .
JUST GET OUT !
[ Clattering ] [ Growling ]
[ Growling Continues ]
[ Clattering ]
- HEY , GUYS ! COME ON , MAN ! - [ Sarah ] FOR GOODNESS SAKE !
[ Men Grunting , Muttering ]
I 'M ALL RIGHT . THANKS , BILL .
I 'M ALL RIGHT . HERE .
I 'VE JUST FILLED IT UP . GOT A REFILL AS WELL .
NO , THANKS . I 'M ALL RIGHT . REALLY .
IT 'S JUST BRANDY . GOOD FOR THE HEART .
IT 'S SHIT FOR YOUR HEART , AND IT EATS UP YOUR LIVER .
[ Coughs ]
WE DON 'T GET A LOT OF VISITORS OUT HERE , AND WE LIKE IT THAT WAY .
HERE IT IS : THE RITZ .
MADAM .
JOHN 'S PROBABLY OUT THE BACK .
HEY ! WELL , WHAT DO YOU KNOW .
WELCOME TO CIVILIZATION , SARAH .
THE LAST HOLDOUT . IT 'S PRETTY NICE .
NICER THAN WE GOT INSIDE .
- NOT A BAD IDEA . - IT 'S A LITTLE SAFER WHERE YOU ARE .
BUT WE LIKE TO LIVE DANGEROUSLY , BILLY BOY AND ME , YOU KNOW .
THAT 'S A LAUGH . I HAVEN 'T SEEN YOU DO ANYTHING DANGEROUS SINCE WE GOT HERE .
WE STICKIN ' AROUND . THAT 'S GETTIN ' A BIT DANGEROUS ,
AS I HOPE YOU NOTICED THIS EVENING .
YOU 'RE A MYSTERY TO ME .
YOU REALLY ARE .
NOT LIKE THOSE OTHER GOONS IN THERE .
YOU HAVE A SENSE OF- - [ Scoffs ]
OF WHAT ? [ Chuckles ] NEVER MIND .
NO , NO , NO . COME ON . LET 'S TALK ABOUT IT .
I CAME DOWN HERE TO GET DRUNK . I DON 'T HAVE THE ENERGY .
HEY , HEY . IT TAKES MORE ENERGY TO KEEP QUIET THAN IT DOES TO SPEAK THE MIND .
GO AHEAD . LET GO OF WHAT YOU GOT , NOW .
YOU WERE SENT DOWN HERE TO DO A JOB .
MY JOB IS TO FLY THE WHIRLYBIRD . I 'VE BEEN DOIN ' THAT JOB JUST FINE .
YOU HAVE THE PROTECTION OF THIS FACILITY . YOU EAT OUR FOOD . YOU DRINK OUR WATER .
AND YOU DON 'T LIFT A FINGER TO HELP . NEITHER ONE OF YOU .
[ John Laughing ]
WE DON 'T BELIEVE IN WHAT YOU 'RE DOIN ' HERE , SARAH .
HEY , YOU KNOW WHAT ALL THEY KEEP DOWN HERE IN THIS CAVE ?
MAN , THEY GOT THE BOOKS AND THE RECORDS OF THE TOP 500 COMPANIES .
THEY GOT THE DEFENSE DEPARTMENT BUDGET DOWN HERE .
AND THEY GOT THE NEGATIVE FOR ALL YOUR FAVORITE MOVIES .
THEY GOT MICROFILM WITH TAX RETURN AND NEWSPAPER STORIES .
THEY GOT IMMIGRATION RECORDS , CENSUS REPORTS ,
AND THEY GOT OFFICIAL ACCOUNTS OF ALL THE WARS AND PLANE CRASHES ...
AND VOLCANO ERUPTIONS AND EARTHQUAKES AND FIRES AND FLOODS- -
AND ALL THE OTHER DISASTERS THAT INTERRUPTED THE FLOW OF THINGS ...
IN THE GOOD OLD U.S. OF A.
NOW , WHAT DOES IT MATTER , SARAH DARLING ?
ALL THIS FILING AND RECORD KEEPING ?
WE EVER GONNA GIVE A SHIT ? WE EVEN GONNA GET A CHANCE TO SEE IT ALL ?
THIS IS A GREAT BIG 14-MILE TOMBSTONE !
[ Voice Echoing ] TOMBSTONE ! [ Distant Moaning ]
WITH AN EPITAPH ON IT THAT NOBODY GONNA BOTHER TO READ .
NOW , HERE YOU COME- - HERE YOU COME WITH A WHOLE NEW SET OF CHARTS ...
AND GRAPHS AND RECORDS .
WHAT YOU GONNA DO ? BURY THEM DOWN HERE WITH ALL THE OTHER RELICS ...
OF WHAT ONCE WAS ?
LET ME TELL YOU WHAT ELSE . YEAH , I 'M GONNA TELL YOU WHAT ELSE .
YOU AIN 'T NEVER GONNA FIGURE IT OUT , JUST LIKE THEY NEVER FIGURED OUT ...
WHY THE STARS ARE WHERE THEY 'RE AT .
IT AIN 'T MANKIND 'S JOB TO FIGURE THAT STUFF OUT .
SO WHAT YOU 'RE DOIN' IS A WASTE OF TIME , SARAH .
AND TIME IS ALL WE GOT LEFT , YOU KNOW .
WHAT I 'M DOING ... IS ALL THERE 'S LEFT TO DO .
SHAME ON YOU . THERE 'S PLENTY TO DO .
PLENTY TO DO . SO LONG AS THERE 'S YOU AND ME AND MAYBE SOME OTHER PEOPLE ,
WE COULD START OVER , START FRESH , GET SOME BABIES .
AND TEACH ' EM , SARAH , TEACH ' EM NEVER TO COME OVER HERE ...
- AND DIG THESE RECORDS OUT . - [ Distant Moaning ]
HEY .
YOU WANT TO PUT SOME KIND OF EXPLANATION ...
DOWN HERE BEFORE YOU LEAVE ?
HERE 'S ONE AS GOOD AS ANY YOU 'RE LIKELY TO FIND .
WE 'RE BEING PUNISHED BY THE CREATOR .
HE VISITED A CURSE ON US ...
SO WE MAN COULD LOOK AT ...
WHAT HELL WAS LIKE .
MAYBE DIDN 'T WANT TO SEE US BLOW OURSELVES UP ...
AND PUT A BIG HOLE IN HIS SKY .
MAYBE HE JUST WANTED TO SHOW US HE WAS STILL THE BOSS MAN .
MAYBE HE FIGURE ... WE WAS GETTING TOO BIG FOR OUR BRITCHES ...
TRYING TO FIGURE HIS SHIT OUT .
[ Growling ] [ Fisher ] YOU SON OF A BITCH !
[ Continues Growling ]
[ Fisher ] DAMN IT !
IT 'S NO GOOD .
IT 'S NO FUCKIN ' GOOD . WHAT IS THAT STUFF ?
IT 'S SOMETHING CALLED BEEF TREATS , WHICH THE ARMY PROVIDES US WITH ...
SO GENEROUSLY .
- HE WON 'T TOUCH IT . - SHIT . I WOULDN 'T EITHER .
SORRY . WE 'RE FRESH OUT OF FILET MIGNON .
- [ Groaning Continues ] - WHAT IS THIS ? PART OF LOGAN 'S PLAN ...
TO TRY AND SOCIALIZE THESE THINGS ?
HE TOLD ME HIMSELF THEY DON 'T EAT FOR NOURISHMENT . WHAT ARE WE HOPING FOR HERE ?
HOPING TO SATISFY THE URGE . YOU SEE , SARAH , THEY 'RE- -
THEY ARE US . THEY ARE THE EXTENSIONS OF US .
THEY ARE THE SAME ANIMAL , SIMPLY FUNCTIONING LESS PERFECTLY .
THEY CAN BE FOOLED , YOU SEE ? THEY CAN BE TRICKED INTO BEING GOOD LITTLE GIRLS AND BOYS ,
THE SAME WAY WE WERE TRICKED INTO IT ON THE PROMISE OF SOME REWARD TO COME .
[ Moaning ] THEY HAVE TO BE REWARDED .
REWARD IS THE KEY . I 'M CONVINCED OF THAT NOW .
COME . I 'VE GOT SOMETHING TO SHOW YOU .
THAT WASN 'T VERY NICE , YOU KNOW . THAT WASN 'T VERY NICE AT ALL .
LET 'S GO .
AND YOU CAN JUST SIT THERE IN THE DARK AND THINK ABOUT WHAT YOU 'VE DONE .
THINK ABOUT IT . THINK .
[ Moaning Over P.A. , Feedback ] I CALL HIM BUB .
THAT 'S WHAT THE CLUB FELLAS USED TO CALL MY FATHER . CAN YOU IMAGINE A SURGEON CALLED BUB ?
NOBODY SEEMED TO MIND , THOUGH . HE WAS RICH .
[ Moaning ] MY FATHER WAS RICH .
HE USED TO SAY I 'D NEVER BE RICH DOING PURE RESEARCH .
I 'D NEVER BE RICH .
UH , BUB 'S BEEN RESPONDING SO WELL LATELY , I 'VE LET HIM LIVE .
WELL , IS HE ALIVE OR DEAD ? WELL , THAT 'S THE QUESTION THESE DAYS , ISN 'T IT ?
WELL , LET 'S SAY THAT I LET HIM CONTINUE TO EXIST .
HELLO , BUB ! [ Both Snickering ]
[ Over P.A. ] HERE ARE SOME TOYS FOR YOU .
SOME NICE THINGS FOR YOU TO PLAY WITH .
YOU REMEMBER THEM FROM BEFORE ? FROM BEFORE .
WELL , HE 'S SEEN THE OTHER THINGS BEFORE , BUT THE BOOK IS NEW .
LOOK , LOOK , LOOK .
I THOUGHT HE 'D DO THAT . [ Scribbling ]
[ Moaning ]
- OPEN IT UP . - [ Gasps ]
HE REMEMBERS . HE REMEMBERS EVERYTHING THAT HE USED TO .
BUB , I 'M VERY PLEASED . VERY PLEASED .
WHAT 'S HE TRYING TO PROVE ?
I SAW ONE OF THOSE THINGS SITTIN ' IN A CAR IN D.C ... .
TRYIN ' TO DRIVE DOWN INDEPENDENCE AVENUE .
IT DIDN 'T MAKE ME WANNA BE ITS FRIEND . NO . IT 'S AMAZING .
IT 'S NOT WHAT THIS ONE DOES , BUT WHAT HE DOESN 'T DO .
WHAT DO YOU MEAN ? HE DOESN 'T GET EXCITED ...
AND DOESN 'T GET AGITATED WHEN LOGAN WALKS IN THE ROOM .
HE DOESN 'T SEE LOGAN AS- - LUNCH .
DINNER . BREAKFAST .
HAVING FUN ? WHAT 'S HE DOIN' IN THERE ?
[ Logan ] NO NEED FOR THAT , CAPTAIN . HE 'S QUITE DOCILE .
COME IN . YOU CAN ALL COME IN .
BUB WON 'T MIND .
[ Moans ]
EXTRAORDINARY , ISN 'T IT ?
THAT 'S RIGHT , BUB . SAY HELLO .
COME ON , CAPTAIN . GIVE ME A BREAK , WILL YA ?
SAY HELLO TO YOUR AUNT ALICIA .
SAY , " HELLO , AUNT ALICIA . "
" HELLO , AUNT ALICIA . "
[ Moaning , Muffled ] HEL-LO , AUNT ALICIA . " HELLO . "
[ Logan ] APPARENTLY , HE WAS IN THE MILITARY . RETURN THE SALUTE AND SEE WHAT HE DOES .
YOU WANT ME TO SALUTE THAT PILE OF WALKING PUS ?
SALUTE MY ASS .
YOUR IGNORANCE IS EXCEEDED ONLY BY YOUR CHARM , CAPTAIN .
HOW ARE WE GOING TO SET AN EXAMPLE FOR THEM IF WE BEHAVE BARBARICALLY ?
TAKE THE BULLETS OUT , PLEASE , AND LET ME HAVE YOUR PISTOL , SARAH .
[ Steel Laughing Hysterically ]
[ Moaning ]
[ Gun Cocks ]
IT 'S EMPTY , CAPTAIN . WE SAW THE BULLETS COME OUT .
LET 'S SEE WHAT HE DOES . LET 'S SEE WHAT BUB DOES IN THIS SITUATION .
[ Gun Clicks ]
[ Moans ]
JESUS ... CHRIST .
WHAT ARE WE SUPPOSED TO DO ? TEACH ' EM TRICKS ?
WHAT THE FUCK IS WRONG WITH YOU PEOPLE ? THEY 'RE DEAD !
THEY 'RE FUCKING DEAD , AND YOU WANNA TEACH ' EM TRICKS ?
THEY HAVE TO BE REWARDED , CAPTAIN . WHY ELSE WILL THEY DO WHAT WE WANT THEM TO DO ?
I DON 'T WANT ' EM TO DO ANYTHING BUT DROP OVER !
YES , WELL , APPARENTLY THEY 'RE NOT INCLINED TO DO THAT FOR YOU , CAPTAIN .
IS THIS YOUR PROGRESS ?
IS THIS THE SHIT THAT 'S SUPPOSED TO KNOCK OUR SOCKS OFF ?
IT 'S THE BEGINNING , YES . IT 'S THE BARE BEGINNING OF SOCIAL BEHAVIOR .
OF CIVILIZED BEHAVIOR .
CIVIL BEHAVIOR IS WHAT DISTINGUISHES US FROM THE LOWER FORMS .
IT 'S WHAT ENABLES US TO COMMUNICATE ,
TO GO ABOUT THINGS IN AN ORDERLY FASHION , WITHOUT ATTACKING EACH OTHER LIKE BEASTS .
CIVILITY MUST BE REWARDED , CAPTAIN .
IF IT ISN 'T REWARDED ,
THERE 'S NO USE FOR IT .
THERE 'S JUST NO USE FOR IT AT ALL .
- [ Grunting ] - [ Zombie Growling ]
[ Growling Continues ]
- ' POSSUM READY ? - [ Growling ]
COME ON . GRAB IT . COME ON .
YOU GOT IT ?
HEY . YOU GOT IT ?
[ Growling Continues ]
NO !
NO ! NO !
MILLER ! MILLER !
- [ Screaming ] - [ Gunshots ]
I CAN 'T DO IT . I CAN 'T DO IT !
- [ Screaming ] I CAN 'T DO IT . - [ Moaning ]
[ Yelling ] [ Growling ]
[ Screaming ]
- [ Gunshot ] - [ Continues Screaming ]
[ Groaning ]
[ Departing Footsteps ]
DON 'T LET THIS HAPPEN .
DON 'T LET THIS HAPPEN TO ME . I DON 'T WANNA BE ONE OF THEM .
TAKE ME . PLEASE . TAKE ME . [ Gasping ]
[ Gunshot ]
[ Body Thudding ]
[ Bats Screeching ] [ Miguel Yelps ]
[ Miguel Yelling , Screaming ]
[ Miguel Grunts ]
I NEED FIRE .
[ Screaming ]
[ Men Talking , Indistinct ]
JESUS , MARY AND JOSEPH !
[ Weapon Cocking ]
[ Panting ] GET OUT OF THE WAY , LADY .
NO . I AMPUTATED THE INFECTED AREA . I THINK I CAUGHT IT IN TIME .
YEAH ? BUT WHAT IF YOU DIDN 'T ?
IF I DIDN 'T , I 'LL SHOOT HIM MYSELF .
IT 'S THE SPICK .
THE YELLOW SON OF A BITCH . IT 'S HIS FAULT THIS HAPPENED . IT 'S HIS YELLOW FUCKIN ' FAULT .
GET OUT OF THE WAY , BITCH , OR I 'LL GO RIGHT THROUGH YOU WITH THIS .
WE 'RE GETTING TO MAKE THIS A HABIT , MAN- - POINTING GUNS AT EACH OTHER , YOU KNOW .
WE JUST LOST TWO MEN 'CAUSE OF THIS MOTHERFUCKER .
WELL ... THAT KINDA EVENS THE ODDS BETWEEN US THEN .
[ Steel ] THE SPICK 'S BEEN BIT , CAPTAIN . WE GOTTA BLAST HIM .
HE 'S BEEN BIT ! I GOT THE INFECTION IN TIME .
THAT 'S BULLSHIT , LADY .
I SEEN A THOUSAND OF ' EM . HE 'S GONNA DIE .
IF HE DIES , I 'LL DESTROY HIM MYSELF .
UNLESS HE GETS YOU FIRST .
YOU MAY STILL WANT TO SLEEP WITH HIM .
I DON 'T WANT HIM INSIDE THE COMPLEX .
WE 'LL KEEP HIM OUT HERE , WITH US .
WE GOTTA BLAST HIM , CAPTAIN .
THAT 'D BE DOIN ' ' IM A FAVOR , STEEL .
YOU THINK HE WANTS TO WALK AROUND AFTER HE 'S DEAD ?
YOU THINK HE WANTS TO BE ONE OF THOSE THINGS ?
THINK ABOUT IT , LADY .
AND THINK ABOUT THIS , ALL OF YA- -
FROM NOW ON , YOU AIN 'T GETTIN ' SHIT FROM ME AND MY MEN .
TOMORROW MORNING , WE 'RE GOING INSIDE THAT CORRAL , AND WE AIN 'T COMIN ' OUT ...
TILL EVERY ONE OF THOSE ROTTEN PILES OF GARBAGE HAS BEEN WASTED .
COME ON , STEEL .
[ Shouting ] GET OUT OF THERE , STEEL ! WE GOT BETTER THINGS TO DO !
YOU 'RE ON MY SHIT LIST , FLYBOY .
[ Holsters Gun ]
THANK YOU .
LET 'S TAKE HIM INSIDE , CLEAN HIM UP .
THINK YOU CAN MOVE HIM ?
I-I THINK SO .
[ Torch Clatters ]
[ Sobbing ]
IT 'S ALL RIGHT . IT 'S OKAY .
SHH , SHH , SHH .
SHH , SHH .
- IT 'S A MAN 'S SWEATER . TRY IT ON . - THANKS .
I HAVE TO GO TO THE LAB .
HE 'S GOING TO NEED SOME MORPHINE ...
ALONG WITH SOME OTHER SUPPLIES .
I 'D BETTER GO ALONG . I 'M SURE THOSE BOYS HAVEN 'T CALMED THEMSELVES DOWN YET .
I 'M SORRY I SAID THOSE THINGS ABOUT YOU .
I 'M SORRY TOO . REALLY .
WELL , WHAT DO YOU KNOW ?
WE ARE HEROES AFTER ALL .
WHAT A RELIEF .
SARAH .
HE MIGHT NOT MAKE IT , YOU KNOW .
I KNOW IT .
AT LEAST WE GAVE HIM A CHANCE .
I 'LL KEEP AN EYE ON HIM .
HEY .
YOU GUYS BE CAREFUL . YOU 'RE NOT BACK IN HALF AN HOUR , I 'M COMING OUT TO LOOK FOR YOU .
THEY 'LL LEAVE US ALONE .
HALF AN HOUR .
WE 'LL BE BACK .
[ Liquid Bubbling ]
JESUS GOD ALMIGHTY .
THE RESIDENT SURGEON HAS BEEN BURNING THE MIDNIGHT OILS .
WHAT THE HELL HAS HE BEEN DOIN' DOWN HERE , SLAUGHTERING CATTLE ?
IN HIS MIND , THAT 'S PROBABLY NOT FAR FROM THE TRUTH .
[ Clicks , Rewinds ]
[ Stops ]
[ Man On Tape ] GRANDFATHER 'S TALKING . HIS MIND 'S TALKING .
THERE . I 'VE PUT IT AWAY . I 'VE PUT IT AWAY , MOTHER . I 'VE PUT IT AWAY .
- BASTARD . BE CIVILIZED ! BE CIVIL . - [ Man Groaning , Growling ]
CHRIST ! TAKE THAT OFF .
TAKE THAT OFF ! TAKE THAT OFF ! [ Groaning , Growling Continues ]
FIVE MINUTES , MOTHER . JUST FIVE MINUTES .
OH , MY GOD .
[ Tape Continues , Indistinct ]
- [ Crashes ] - NO , SARAH ! DON 'T !
IT 'LL JUST BRING OUT RHODES AND THE MEN .
LEAVE IT BE , LEAVE IT BE .
LET 'S GO . LET 'S GET OUTTA HERE .
I 'M BEGINNING TO THINK WE SHOULD TAKE THAT HELICOPTER BEFORE SOMEBODY ELSE DOES .
[ Door Opens , Shuts ]
[ Faint Groaning ]
HELLO , BUB .
MOTHER IS VERY PROUD OF YOU .
VERY , VERY PROUD INDEED .
YOU DID QUITE NICELY TODAY .
[ Groaning ]
? [ Choir : " Ode To Joy " ]
[ Soft Groaning ]
- [ Clicks Off ] - [ Angry Groaning ]
? [ Resumes ]
I DON 'T BELIEVE IT . LOGAN 'S STAR PUPIL .
- NOW , TOMORROW , WE CAN PLAY WITH THESE THINGS AGAIN . - [ Clicks Off ]
NOW IT 'S TIME FOR YOUR REWARD .
I BROUGHT YOU SOMETHING GOOD .
[ Groans ]
WHAT IS THAT ?
IS THAT- -
IT CAN 'T BE .
OH , GOD . I CAN 'T LOOK . CAN 'T- - [ Gasps ]
- [ Soft Groan ] - GOOD NIGHT , BUB .
WHAT ARE YOU GIVIN ' HIM IN THERE , FRANKENSTEIN ? WHAT ?
- HUUH ! - WHAT IS IT , HUH ?
WHAT DO YOU GIVE HIM ?
SCUM !
NO , YOU- - YOU MUST LISTEN TO ME , CAPTAIN . YOU MUST LISTEN .
LISTEN TO THIS .
HOLD IT , FISHER .
TORREZ , GET HIS GUN .
TAKE ALL THE GUNS .
ALL OF ' EM . ALL THEIR FUCKING GUNS !
TAKE ALL THEIR GUNS .
ALL THEIR GUNS !
THOSE ARE MY MEN IN THERE .
MY MEN . [ Shouting ] THOSE ARE MY MEN IN THERE !
[ Rhodes Talking , Indistinct ]
HOLD IT RIGHT THERE .
FRANKENSTEIN 'S DEAD .
THIS SCUM GETS IT NEXT UNLESS YOU THROW YOUR WEAPONS OUT RIGHT NOW .
HE MEANS IT , JOHNNY . HE KILLED LOGAN IN COLD BLOOD .
I KILLED LOGAN BECAUSE HE WAS A BUTCHER .
I 'LL KILL THE REST OF THEM ONE AT A TIME , UNLESS YOU GET YOUR BLACK ASS OUT HERE , FLYBOY .
- LET HIM GO , RHODES . - TORREZ , GET HIS MACHETE .
WE 'RE GETTIN ' OUTTA HERE RIGHT NOW .
YOU GIVE ME ANY SHIT ABOUT IT , I BLOW HIS HEAD OFF .
WHIRLYBIRD CAN 'T HOLD US ALL .
" US ALL " AIN 'T GOING . ME , MY MEN , YOU . THAT 'S IT .
YOU 'LL NEVER GET ME TO DO THAT , RHODES .
NO ! HEY !
RICKLES , OPEN THE GATES . STEEL , SHOVE ' EM IN THERE .
[ Indistinct Talking , Laughing ]
HAVE A NICE VISIT WITH McDERMOTT , HUH ?
[ Zombies Growling ]
RHODES ... DON 'T DO THIS , PLEASE .
GONNA GIVE US A RIDE , FLYBOY ?
I 'LL DO WHATEVER YOU SAY , MAN . LET HER GO NOW .
RHODES . LET ' EM OFF .
I 'LL TAKE YOU ... WHEREVER YOU WANT TO GO .
LIKE YOU SAID , CHOPPER CAN 'T HOLD US ALL .
[ John ] RHODES , DON 'T DO IT .
YOU DO IT , AND I WON 'T FLY .
I SWEAR , YOU GOT TO KILL ME BEFORE I FLY .
LET ' EM OUT . THAT 'S THE DEAL .
I MAKE THE DEALS AROUND HERE , NOT YOU .
NOW YOU GET YOUR SHIT TOGETHER , WHATEVER YOU NEED .
ISN 'T THERE AN OLD SILO BACK THERE ?
NO . WE CAN 'T GO BACK THERE WITHOUT GUNS .
- [ Sarah ] WE CAN 'T STAY HERE . THEY 'LL TEAR US APART . - OH , JESUS , MARY AND JOSEPH .
DON 'T SHOOT ' IM !
WE NEED HIS ASS .
STEEL , KICK HIM AROUND A LITTLE BIT .
MIGHT KNOCK SOME SENSE INTO THAT JUNGLE-BUNNY HEAD .
- [ Rickles ] CAPTAIN ! - [ Rhodes ] THAT 'S IT .
RUN , YOU FUCKIN ' LUNATICS .
[ Zombies Groaning ]
OH !
UUH !
[ Grunting ]
THEY 'RE GONE , FLYBOY . LET 'S GO .
NOT A CHANCE .
[ Whirring , Beeping ]
- JESUS CHRIST . THAT 'S THE ELEVATOR . - CHECK IT OUT .
[ Lips Smacking ]
[ Groans ]
[ Zombie Groaning ] AW , JESUS .
ROCK SLIDE . WE CAN 'T GET THROUGH .
THIS WAY . WE CAN TRY AND GET AROUND .
[ Groaning ] AAH !
[ Shrieking ]
- [ Screams ] - [ Gurgling ]
[ Gasps ] OH , IT 'S YOU . THIS WAY .
[ Bat Screeches ]
LET 'S GO , TORREZ . GET UP .
[ Gunshots ]
UUH !
AW , SHIT ! SOMEBODY TOOK THIS APART .
THE ONLY OTHER CONTROL 'S UP ON THE PLATFORM WITH A HAND BOX .
STUCK .
- RICKLES , WE CAN 'T GET OUT OF HERE . - FIX IT . CAN 'T YOU FIX IT ?
IT 'S THAT FUCKIN ' SPICK THAT DID THIS ! FIX IT !
COME ON , MAN ! FIX WHAT ?
FIX THE BOX , MAN ! COME ON ! FIX IT ! THEY TORE THE GUTS OUT !
I CAN 'T FIX IT ! WE GOT THE BOOK HERE ! WE CAN FIX IT !
THE BASTARD .
[ Bat Screeches ]
SARAH ! [ Echoing ]
WILLIE ! [ Echoing ]
JOHN ! [ Echoing ]
[ Groaning ]
[ Gunshot ]
[ Distant Gunshots ]
[ Zombie Groaning ]
UUH ! [ Barks ]
LET 'S KEEP MOVING .
[ Growling ]
AHA !
[ Grunts ]
UUH !
[ Groaning ]
[ Zombies Groaning ]
[ Muffled Scream ]
HOLD DOWN . AW , FUCK !
WHAT 'S GOIN ' ON ? THAT SPICK .
HE RIPPED THESE CONTROLS OUT , THE LITTLE YELLOW BASTARD .
THE LITTLE SHIT .
THE LITTLE FUCKIN ' SHIT .
YOU TRIED TO MAKE A RUN FOR IT .
[ Whirring , Beeping ]
[ Steel ] HOLY SHIT .
HOLY FUCKIN ' SHIT .
[ Shouting ] RHODES !
RHODES , YOU BASTARD !
[ Moans Softly ]
[ Wailing ]
[ Sniffling ]
[ Screaming ]
OH , SHIT !
AAH ! SHIT !
FUCK !
HA , HA !
[ Whooping ]
HOLY SHIT ! [ Cackling ]
[ Screaming ]
SHIT !
RHODES ! GODDAMN , RHODES !
OPEN THE DOOR , YOU SON OF A BITCH !
RHODES !
SHIT ! [ Gunshot ]
[ Nasally Voice ] COME ON , BUB .
COME ON , YOU PUS-BRAINED BAG OF SHIT .
YOU WANNA LEARN HOW TO SHOOT , BUB ? I 'LL TEACH YOU HOW TO SHOOT .
COME ON , YOU BAG OF- - [ Growling ]
[ Screaming ]
- [ Zombies Groaning ] - OH !
[ Sarah ] LET 'S GO . FOLLOW THE RED LIGHTS .
- IT 'S TEMPORARILY OUT OF SERVICE . - THE LADDER ! GO AHEAD . UP , UP .
UP !
[ Screeching ]
[ Growling ]
[ Gunshot ]
COME ALONG , JOHNNY .
WE 'RE COUNTIN ' ON YA TO FLY US TO THE PROMISED LAND .
COME ON , COME ON . COME ON !
OH , SHIT !
AAH !
UUH !
YOU FUCK .
AAH !
[ Groans ]
YOU PUS FUCK ! YOU FUCK !
YOU PUS FUCK ! YOU PUS FUCK !
[ Screaming ]
YOU F- - AAH !
COME ON !
COME ON ! COME O-O-ON !
COME O-O-ON !
[ Zombies Gasping Delightedly ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Gasping ] SALAZAR !
SALAZAR !
[ Ghostly Moaning ]
[ John ] LET 'S HOPE THEY FILLED UP THE GAS TANK FROM THE OTHER NIGHT .
OH , MY GOD . COME ON , COME ON !
[ John ] GET IN , GET IN !
AAH ! [ Screams ]
[ Gulls Cawing ]
? EYES ?
? EYES , EYES ?
? IS IT YOU ?
? IS IT ME ?
? HOLDING ON FOR SO LONG ?
? TRYING DESPERATELY ?
? IS IT RIGHT ?
? OH-OH-OH , IS IT FAIR ?
? WANTING MORE , SO MUCH MORE ?
? AND IT 'S NEVER THERE ?
? I AM WITH YOU WHEN ?
? I FEEL LIKE I 'M ?
? ALONE ?
? IT 'S EASY TO PRETEND ?
? THIS WORLD COULD NEVER END ?
? ? COME TAKE MY HEART , MY SOUL ?
? MY LOVE ?
? MY LIFE ?
? TONIGHT ?
? LOVE ME ?
? TONIGHT , BABE ?
? ? TAKE ME TO THE WORLD INSIDE ?
? YOUR EYES ?
? TONIGHT ?